减速  停一下
Hey! Slow down! Slow down!
停下...  求你们了
Slow-- I'm begging you!
行行好吧
Please!
(艾琳)
捂住耳朵
Cover your ears.
这样应该可以了
Yeah, this'll work.
弄好了叫我
Tell me when.
把碎石和树枝用布包上
Put something under the car like this
放在车下面
with a little gravel and sticks.
增加摩擦力
It gives you traction.
都怪她把车开到泥里
Wouldn't have to do it if she didn't get us stuck.
她不是故意的
It was an honest mistake.
为什么要让她跟着
Why'd you let her come?
她把你引到伍德伯里
She took you to Woodbury
你说她半路失踪
and you said split on you.
-奥斯卡因此而死...  -事情并不那么简单
- And Oscar died and you guys-- - It wasn't that simple.
我今天之所以带上她
I asked her to come today.
是因为我不在监狱  我不想把她留在那儿
I didn't want to leave her at the prison if I wasn't there,
和莫尔一起
not with Merle.
况且我俩利益相同
That and we got common interests.
就目前来看  我们是一条船上的人
For right now, we have the same problems.
说不定还可以联合作战
So maybe we can work on them together.
只是目前吗
Just for right now?
对  暂时而已
Yeah, just for right now.
救救我
Help me!
求你们了  千万别走
I'm begging you! Don't leave!
行行好吧
Please!
别走
Don't leave!
别丢下我
Please!
我们走
Let's go.
我没被咬
I'm okay!
别走
Please!
别走啊
救救我
Help me!
别走
Stop!
《行尸走肉》
该死
Damn it!
镇上还有其它警察局吗
You got any other police stations in town?
我原来就是这的警察
I was the police here.
我和其他几个人
Me and a few other guys.
这个镇不大
Ain't a big town.
还有其它地方可以找一下
There's other places to check.
也许枪没有这多  但是
May not have as many guns as were in here, but--
这有多少枪我们都得带回去
We need as many guns as were in here.
-弹药也是  -是的
- Ammo, too. - Yeah, we do.
但是现在  我只知道几个地方
But right now, I only got a line on a couple.
主街道上有几个地方
There's a few places out on the main street--
酒吧  还有一个烟酒店
bars, a liquor store.
店主都有一两把枪  放在柜台后面
Owners had a gun or two behind the counter
大家当时都不知道
that people didn't know about.
我知道  我签了枪支许可证
I did. I signed the permits.
那些枪可能还在那
They might still be there.
你对我的想法有意见吗
Do you have a problem with that approach?
没有  瑞克  我没有意见
No, Rick. I don't have a problem.
(远离此地)
-这是什么  -我不知道
- What is it? - I don't know.
(不用内疚  你知道的)
(往回走  别找死)
(听忠告)
(混蛋)
看起来有人已经占了这里了
It's looks like someone already made these theirs.
并不意味着他们拿走了我们要找的东西
Doesn't mean they found what we're looking for.
有几个地方就在前面
Couple of the places are just up ahead.
我们进去拿了枪
Let's get in
赶快离开这
and get the hell out of here.
就在那
There.
提利尔家
Tyrell's.
一把猎枪  两把手枪
A shotgun and two handguns.
核发提利尔·迪比的枪支许可
License issued to Tyrell Debbs.
等等
Wait.
她会被绊住的
She'll get caught.
举起手
Hands!
放下手中的东西  离开这
Now you drop what you got and you go.
放下你们的枪  鞋子  还有那把刀
Your guns, your shoes, and that sword.
所有东西  限你们十秒钟
All of it. 10 seconds.
-往车那跑  -十
- Run for the car now. - Ten...
-爸爸  -我们需要那把步枪
- Dad. - We need that rifle.
九
...nine,
八
eight...
-我能上去  -七
- I think I can get up there. - ...seven,
-六  -卡尔  快跑
- six... - Carl, go.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
我让你往车那跑
I told you to run for the car.
我不想让你做这种事
I didn't want you to have to do that.
我必须得做
I had to.
他穿着防弹衣
He's wearing body armor.
-他还活着  -和我们有关系吗
- He's alive. - Do we care?
有
Yeah.
小心陷阱
Keep an eye out for booby traps.
看起来他防人之心很重
Looks like he's gotten pretty creative so far.
我们不是进去拿了枪就回去吗
I thought we were just gonna get in and get the hell out of here.
我不能抛下他
I'm not leaving on the street.
听着  我知道你说他帮过你
Look, I know you said he helped you.
他救了我的命
He saved my life.
他原来不是这样的
He wasn't like this then.
好吧
Okay.
天啊  他还有个儿子
Jesus, he has a son.
你认为他在里面吗
You think he's in there?
(欢迎)
别动
Don't.
小心有陷阱
You said booby traps.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我们把他搬进去就走
Let's just get him inside and go.
(危险  没骗你)
(没骗你吧)
卡尔  小心金属线
Carl, watch the wire.
我去年带他去过武器库
I showed him that weapons locker last year.
那里面有这么多武器
And it had all of this in it?
不  这还不到一半
No, not even half.
他一直没闲着  有床
He's been busy. The cot.
(清醒)
(门把手  手中刀)
(德韦恩变行尸了)
不
No.
我们等他醒来
We're gonna wait for him to wake up.
确保他没事
Make sure he's okay.
他想杀死我们
He tried to kill us.
他让我们离开  他不知道我们是谁
He told us to go. He didn't know who we were.
他试图杀我们  我们没把他留给行尸
He tried to kill us and we didn't leave him for the walkers.
他够走运了  他也不需要这么多武器
He's had a good day. He doesn't need half of these guns.
而我们急需
We do.
我们等他醒过来  不要说了
We're waiting for him to wake up. That's it.
你好好看过这个地方了吗
Have you taken a look around this place?
斧子  矛  墙上的字
The axe, the spikes, the walls.
-你觉得他疯了吗  -不
- You think he's crazy? - No.
我觉得他很危险
I think he's dangerous.
我认识他
I know him.
你认识的是以前的他
He wasn't like this then.
我们等他醒过来
We're gonna wait for him to wake up.
你看什么呢
What do you see?
这是我们的社区
It's our neighborhood.
(瑞克家  已烧光)
房子没了
It's gone.
这就是你跟来的原因
Is that why you wanted to come?
想看看咱们家的房子
To see the house?
卡尔
Carl.
我就是想来
I just wanted to come.
你这就开始吃他的东西了
We're eating his food now?
门垫上写着  欢迎
The mat said "Welcome."
(国王郡咖啡馆)
我想去找补给
I'm going on a run.
去哪
Where?
我想人们不会去抢婴儿床的
I thought maybe the one thing people didn't loot was cribs
有个婴儿用品店是妈妈的朋友萨拉开的
and there's that baby place that mom's friend Sara ran.
-就在街角  -卡尔
- It's just around the corner. - Carl.
爸爸  它就在街角
Dad, it's just around the corner.
这到处都有给行尸设下的陷阱
And there's all those walker traps.
你需要帮忙抬箱子
You're gonna need some help carrying the box.
什么
What?
如果你想找个婴儿床  你得先弄个箱子
If you're gonna get the crib, you have to get the box.
那玩意儿又大又重
It's big and heavy.
你得找人帮你搬箱子
You're gonna need help carrying the box.
你是打算弄个婴儿床  没错吧
You are getting a crib, right?
没错
That's what I said.
那我和他一起去
Then I'll go with him.
只能去那  我们说好了
Right there, that's the deal.
如果你遇上麻烦  就大声呼救
You get into trouble, you holler, okay?
-我在这就能听见  -好的
- I'll hear it from here. - Okay.
其实你没必要和我一起来
You don't have to come with me.
我一个人能搞定
I can handle it.
我答应你爸帮你
I told your dad I'd help you.
行  好吧
Yeah, okay.
你得先把那个解决了
Guess we should take care of that.
见鬼
Shit.
你刚刚玩的是哪出
What the hell was that?
我想靠自己的力量办好这事
I want to do this on my own.
你刚走过了婴儿用品店
You've just pass the baby place.
我要先给朱迪思找点别的东西
I'm getting Judith something else first, okay?
真遗憾这些事发生在你身上
I'm sorry this happened to you.
(所有人都不是人)
你知道我是谁吗  你还认得我吗
Do you know who I am? Do you see who I am?
你是戴着死人脸的鬼
People wearing dead people's faces.
-摩根你听我说  -不  我不认识你
- Morgan, listen to me. - No, I don't know you!
-你认识我  -我不认识你
- You do know me. - I don't know you!
你救过我的命  摩根
You saved my life, Morgan.
你绝对认识我
You know me.
仔细看着我
Look at me.
你不清醒了  老兄
You don't clear, man.
你变了
You turn.
你已经死了
You just die.
你认识我
You know me!
我现在谁都不认识了
I don't know anyone anymore!
你不是人
You don't clear!
你认识我
You know me.
你这条疯狗
You crazy son of a bitch.
求你了
Please.
求你杀了我
Please kill me.
求求你杀了我吧
Just kill me.
求你成全了我
求求你了
Just kill me. Just--
让我一了百了吧
just kill me.
去年  你在我家前院找到了我  摩根
You found me last year in my front yard, Morgan.
你和...  你找到了我
You and-- you found me.
你给我吃的  你告诉我发生了什么
You fed me. You told me what's happening.
你救了我的命
You saved me.
我的名字叫瑞克·格兰姆斯  你认识我
My name is Rick Grimes. You know me.
我才没有戴着一张死人脸
I'm not wearing a dead man's face.
我给了你这个
I gave you this.
我说过  每天清晨把它打开
I said, turn it on every day at dawn
这样你就能找到我
so you could find me.
你是瑞克
Rick?
我认识你
I know you.
老兄  见鬼  我...
Oh, man. Damn it, I--
我认识你  我知道你是谁了
I know you. I know who you are.
你说你每天清晨都会打开对讲机
You said you'd turn yours on at dawn.
你是那么说的
That's what you said.
一开始我没准备找你...
I mean, I hadn't worked up to it yet, and--
但后来我找了
then I did.
在房顶上  我和我儿子
On the roof, every morning for days.
呼叫了好几天  好几周
For weeks, me and my boy.
然后...
And then...
只剩下我自己
me.
但里面只有静电噪音  只有噪音
Just static, though. Nothing but static.
后来什么声音都没了
And then nothing but nothing.
你不在  你从没有呼叫过我们
You weren't there. You were never there.
我呼叫过
I was.
不  我找你的时候你从没在过
No, not when I tried.
你说你会每天清晨
I mean, you said you would turn on your radio
-都把对讲机打开  -摩根  我...
- every day at dawn. - Morgan, I--
你说你会每天清晨
You said that you would turn on your radio...
-都把对讲机打开  -我打开了
- Everyday at dawn.  - I did.
但你从没出现过
And you were not there!
我迫不得已越走越远
I kept getting... I kept getting pushed farther out.
我必须那么做  别无选择
I had to. I didn't have a choice.
我找到了我的妻儿
I found my wife and my boy.
还有其他人
I had people.
我有责任保障他们的安全
I had to keep them safe.
我们被逼无奈  越走越远
We kept getting pushed back deeper into the country.
我对天发誓  我别无选择
I swear to God I didn't have a choice.
拿回你的对讲机吧
You can have your radio back
我现在总算是找到你了
'cause it looks like I finay found you.
你找到了你老婆和儿子
You found your wife and your son.
对  你脑子里只有他们
That's what happened right? You found them.
他们有没有...
And did they...
你老婆她...  她...
did she... did your wife...
她变行尸了吗
did she turn?
没有  她死了
No, she died.
那么你没看到她的尸变过程吧
So you didn't have to see that, then.
当然没有
Of course not.
不像我
Not like me.
不
No.
不像我  不像我老婆
Not like me. Not like my wife.
你还记得她经历了什么吗
You remember what happened to her?
你知道她变成什么了吗
You remember what she was?
是啊
Yeah.
不对...
No...
你给过我枪
You gave me the gun.
你尝试过
You tried.
我尝试了什么  摩根
What did I try, Morgan?
我尝试了什么
What did I try?
你尝试让我做该做的事情
You tried to get me to do it 'cause I was supposed to do it.
我应该杀死她  我的珍妮
I was supposed to kill her, my Jenny.
我知道应该杀  但我没有
Knew I was supposed to, but I let it go.
就好像不知道会有报应一样
Let it go like there wasn't gonna be a reckoning.
我们总是在找食物
We was always looking for food.
你懂的  食物最重要
You know, it alway came down to food.
我当时在
And I was--
我当时在检查一个地窖
I was checking out a cellar
我不想让德韦恩一起下去
and I didn't want Duane to come down there with me.
当我上去时
And then when I came up...
她站在他面前
she was standing there right in front of him
他举起了枪
and he had his gun up
却下不了手
and he couldn't do it.
所以我叫了他
So I called to him
他转过身
and he turned.
然后她...
And then she was just--
扑向他
just on him.
我眼前一片一片的血红
And I see red. I see red.
一切都被染成了红色
Everything is red. Everything I see is red.
然后我开枪了
And I do it.
终于下了手
Finally.
但太迟了
Finally was too late.
我早该杀了她
I was supposed to.
我太自私
I was selfish.
太懦弱
I was weak.
你把枪给了我
You gave me the gun.
你的儿子
Hey, your boy--
他死了吗
is he dead?
-没有  -没有
- No. - No?
他会死的
He will be.
因为像你一样的人
See, 'cause people like you,
你们这种好人总会死
the good people, they always die.
坏人也会死
And the bad people do, too.
但懦弱的人
But the weak people,
像我这样的人
the people like me...
我们却生存了下来
we have inherited the earth.
(国王郡咖啡馆)
(欢迎)
你觉得我会让你进去吗
You think I was gonna let you go in there?
我觉得我做什么不关你事
I just think It's none of your business.
你不了解我  不了解我爸爸
You don't know me. You don't know my dad.
我是来帮你的
I came out here to help.
你来是因为利益相同
You came out here for common interests.
我们有共同的敌人和共同的麻烦
We have the same enemy and the same problem.
所以你才来这里  就这么简单
And that's why you're here. That's it.
这事很重要
This is important.
我必须要做
I'm going to do this.
我也知道如何做到
And I know how I can.
你无法阻止我
You can't stop me.
我确实无法阻止你
I can't stop you.
但你也无法阻止我帮助你
But you can't stop me from helping you.
不
No!
-我必须回去  -掉哪里了
- I've got to go back in. - Where is it?
我们得回去  必须回去  我要回去
We have to go back. We have to. I have to.
就剩这一张了
It's the only one left!
-好吧  -这样不行
- Fine. - Not like this.
我知道我不了解你
I don't know you. I get that.
但你能帮我个忙吗
But can you do something for me?
在这里等着
Wait here.
-我能帮上忙  -不用  别说废话了
- I can help. - No. And no more bullshit.
你在这里等我
You wait here.
就这么办
That's how we get it done.
我只是
I just--
我只是觉得朱迪思应该
I just thought Judith should--
应该知道妈妈长什么样
should know what her mom looked like.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我本来也是要回去的
I was gonna go back in anyway.
我可不能把这个留下
I just couldn't leave this behind.
它太可爱了
It's just too damn gorgeous.
我不会杀你的
I'm not gonna kill you.
事情不应该是那样的结局
I don't think that's what's supposed to happen.
我认为你该和我们一起回去
I think you're supposed to come back with us.
在刚发生的一切后吗
After all that?
在我试图轰掉你的脑袋  捅伤你后
After me trying to blow your head off,
我们从此幸福地生活在一起吗
stab your heart out, happily ever after together?
你杀不了我  我也杀不了你
You couldn't kill me, I couldn't kill you.
我觉得这是某种天意
I'll take that as a sign.
我们找到了一座监狱
We found a prison.
监狱的围墙能把行尸挡住
The fences can keep 'em out.
你妻子是在那里死的吧
Is that where your wife died?
你走吧
Just go.
别回来  也别停下
Don't go back. Don't stop.
能活几天多活几天
Just get yourself some more time.
听我说  我能帮你
Look, I can help you.
你可以和我们一起回去  你能痊愈的
You can come back with us. You can heal.
你拿了很多枪  瑞克
You're taking a lot of guns, Rick.
不  我就想说那些枪可不少
No, I'm just saying that that all is a lot of guns.
你需要那么多枪干嘛  瑞克
Why do you need the guns, Rick?
那是因为你如果有什么好东西
'Cause if you got something good,
就一定会有人眼红来抢
that just means that there's someone who wants to take it.
事实就是这样  对吗
And that is what is happening, right?
我们会赢的
We're gonna win.
你可以去我们那里  你能帮上忙
You can be there. You can help.
等着你们的不是尖牙就是子弹
You will be torn apart by teeth or bullets.
你和你儿子
You and your boy.
你手下的人  可我不会
Your people, but not me.
因为我不会再目睹那样的惨剧了
Because I am not gonna watch that happen again.
伙计  你把这些枪拿走吧
Man, you take the guns.
你知道有机会活下去  所以你无法正视
You know there's a chance. That's what you can't square.
这让你心如刀割
That's what hurts.
你知道有机会的
You know there's a chance.
我说的话你一个字也没听进去
I don't think you heard a damn word that I said.
我们的经历一样
We both started out in the same place.
你遭遇了不幸  我也遭遇了不幸
Things went bad for you, things went bad for me.
但你无法正确看待事情
But you're not seeing things right.
我不怪你  你失去了这么多
I don't blame you. What you've lost,
经历了这么多
what you've been through.
导致你无法正确看待事物
you're not seeing things right,
但你能从中恢复  我知道你能做到
but you can come back from this, I know you can.
你也必须做到
You have to.
你一定能振作
This can't be it.
一定能
It can't be.
你一定要恢复过来
You got to be able come back from this.
-不  -摩根  拜托
- No. - Morgan, please.
不
No!
我必须保持清醒
I have to clear.
我今天没死是天意
That's why I didn't die today.
老天让我清醒
That's the sign.
我必须这样  必须的
I have to, man. I have to.
我必须保持清醒
I have to clear.
我正准备找你呢
I was just about to look for you.
-对不起  -没关系
- Sorry. - It's all right.
你不是来了吗
You're here now.
不要紧
Oh, it's nothing.
谢谢
Thank you.
他还好吧
He's okay?
不  他不太好
No, he's not.
等等  喂
Wait. Hey.
-卡尔  -摩根
- Carl. - Morgan.
我必须向你开枪
I had to shoot you.
你能理解我吧
You know I had to, right?
我很内疚
I'm sorry.
听着  孩子
Hey, son.
永远别内疚
Don't ever be sorry.
和她在一起还好吧
Everything okay with her?
我想她跟我们是一路人
I think she might be one of us.
你说什么
What?
一切都好
Everything went okay.
上车吧  我把它放后面
Hop in. I'll throw this in the back.
你出现幻觉了吗
You see something?
我知道你出现幻觉了
I know you see things.
死去的人
People.
我过去也曾和我死去的男友"对话"
I used to talk to my dead boyfriend.
这是正常现象
It happens.
你想开车吗
You wanna drive?
好啊
Yeah.
很好
Good.
我有幻觉
I see things.
(远离此地)